<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<vxml version="2.1">
    <form id="plantingSuggestion">
        <field name="planting">
            <prompt>For planting suggestions based on current and upcoming weather conditions, please select your crop. You can say return to go back the main menu.</prompt>
            <grammar mode="voice" root="item4">
                <rule id="item4">
                    <one-of>
                        <item>Fruit</item>
                        <item>Grains</item>
                        <item>Vegetables</item>
                        <item>Return</item>
                    </one-of>
                </rule>
            </grammar>
            <filled>
                <if cond="planting == 'return'">
                    <prompt>You will return to the main menu.</prompt>
                    <goto next="../main_and_language.xml#mainMenu"/>
                </if>
                <else/>
                    <prompt>You've selected <value expr="planting"/>. Here are the planting practices suggestions for the selected crop based on weather predictions.</prompt>
                </if>
                <break time="3s"/> 
                <goto next="../main_and_language.xml#mainMenu"/>
            </filled>
        </field>
    </form>

    <form id="reportRainfall">
        <field name="rainfall" type="digits">
            <prompt>Contribute to our weather database by reporting rainfall in your area. Please enter the amount of rainfall in your area using the keypad, followed by the # key.</prompt>
            <filled>
                <prompt>The rainfall you report is <value expr="rainfall"/>. Thank you for reporting. Your rainfall data helps improve weather predictions for all farmers.</prompt>
                <break time="3s"/> 
                <goto next="../main_and_language.xml#mainMenu"/>
            </filled>
        </field>
    </form>

    <form id="indigenousKnowledge">
        <field name="knowledge">
            <prompt>
                Explore ancient wisdom for modern farming success. Indigenous knowledge offers unique insights into weather prediction and agricultural adaptation. Please select a topic of interest.
                You can say weather prediction to learn about signs from nature for weather prediction
                You can say weather adaptation to discover traditional farming practices for weather adaptation
                You can say story to hear stories and lessons from local farmers
                You can say return to go back the main menu. 
            </prompt>
            <grammar mode="voice" root="item9">
                <rule id="item9">
                    <one-of>
                        <item>weather prediction</item>
                        <item>weather adaptation</item>
                        <item>story</item>
                        <item>Return</item>
                    </one-of>
                </rule>
            </grammar>
            <filled>
                <if cond="knowledge == 'return'">
                    <prompt>You will return to the main menu.</prompt>
                    <goto next="../main_and_language.xml#mainMenu"/>
                </if>
                <elseif cond="knowledge == 'weather prediction'"/>
                    <prompt>Detailed examples of how specific birds' activities or the appearance of certain plants are traditionally interpreted as signs predicting the start of the rainy season or indicating the expected season's quality.</prompt>
                <elseif cond="knowledge == 'weather adaptation'"/>
                    <prompt>Insights into traditional methods of soil conservation, water management, and crop selection that align with anticipated weather conditions, based on indigenous knowledge.</prompt>
                <elseif cond="knowledge == 'story'"/>
                    <prompt>Narratives and anecdotes from farmers illustrating practical applications of indigenous weather prediction and its impact on agricultural decisions, including how a combination of natural signs guides their preparation for wind and seasonal changes.</prompt>
                </if>
                <break time="3s"/> 
                <goto next="../main_and_language.xml#mainMenu"/>
            </filled>
        </field>
    </form>

    <form id="agriculturalKnowledge">
        <field name="agknowledge">
            <prompt>
                Access daily agricultural tips, updates, and best practices. Please select a category.
                You can say soil for soil management tips. 
                You can say water for water conservation techniques. 
                You can say pest for pest control. 
                You can say crop for crop rotation advice. 
                You can say return to go back the main menu. 
            </prompt>
            <grammar mode="voice" root="item5">
                <rule id="item5">
                    <one-of>
                        <item>soil</item>
                        <item>water</item>
                        <item>pest</item>
                        <item>crop</item>
                        <item>Return</item>
                    </one-of>
                </rule>
            </grammar>
            <filled>
                <if cond="agknowledge == 'return'">
                    <prompt>You will return to the main menu.</prompt>
                    <goto next="../main_and_language.xml#mainMenu"/>
                </if>
                <elseif cond="agknowledge == 'soil'"/>
                    <prompt>Daily tips and best practices in the selected category.</prompt>
                <elseif cond="agknowledge == 'water'"/>
                    <prompt>Daily tips and best practices in the selected category.</prompt>
                <elseif cond="agknowledge == 'pest'"/>
                    <prompt>Daily tips and best practices in the selected category.</prompt>
                <elseif cond="agknowledge == 'crop'"/>
                    <prompt>Daily tips and best practices in the selected category.</prompt>
                </if>
                <break time="3s"/> 
                <goto next="../main_and_language.xml#mainMenu"/>
            </filled>
        </field>
    </form>
</vxml>
